and if you know about math if you've got
this or that two to for 22 things that's
2 to the power of 22 which is a big
number
it's about uh I think it's about 300,000
I think is what the that that is
combinations of
solutions let me just do this just to be
say two to the power
of 22 oh 4 million sorry
4,194 wow thousand so four 4 4.2 million
combinations of solutions when you
thought there was zero to start with wow
now let's get to China and some of the
things that I've been seeing um quite
repetitively is that people are saying
that China is
reporting false statistics false news in
regards to the
um in regards to the the virus like what
are your thoughts on that well what I my
I've got my thoughts and then what I've
heard now uh my thoughts are based on my
information and based on me doing some
logic to try to figure this out yeah and
what I've heard is experiential right
saying about memory somebody told me
this and maybe it's true maybe it's not
I've been hearing the same thing I've
been hearing that it's much bigger than
what they're reporting they say there's
about 4,000 people have it uh I've heard
people say as much as 10 times that uh
I've heard the number
90,000 tossed around
yeah what's true can we actually know
something about it uh we could actually
make a fairly good guess at some things
about this and have a general and take
that General system and apply to other
stuff by the
way so we know from experience that the
Chinese government tends to FIB about
these things there's a thing in Asia
called face or Saving Face we even have
that in in America and the Western world
but not the way they do it there they've
they want to make sure that China looks
good the the government looks good
there's no um there's no chance of
anybody being of overthrowing the
government so they like to really clamp
down on any negative things to come out
well yeah one thing we has come out
they've told about they've bragged about
it is that they're rushing to build a
hospital in six days in the city where
this came out
that seems a little odd why do they need
a hospital if you got 4,000 people sick
you know can't you just put in hospitals
another thing that they did which
they've talked about so we could trust
them at least you know we can trust them
when they say negative stuff because we
know that they tend not that they don't
want to say negative stuff they
quarantined the whole city 50 million
people have been
quarantined now does that sound like
a mild thing if You' got 4,000 people
sick would you lock up 50 million
people how's it going folks Ryan Perez
here with h go live and prosper um we
are on the hustle Zone TV network and
this is brought to you by bowai creative
that's ww. boty creative.com um creative
is spelled with a K so um yeah I wanted
to do this impromptu live because um it
just seems like everyone on my timeline
everyone is talking about the Corona
virus and um how it's
spreading now uh reports there are
reports saying that you know four I
think over 4,000 people are um have um
come in contact with the virus uh and
then there are other reports that are
saying that it's much more than that we
don't know uh so I thought I'd call a
friend of mine um that is like he he is
a mentor uh and I I think he's one of
the smartest people that I know uh to to
come in and weigh on the subject so um
tonight's going to be a treat but I what
I need for everyone in the room um if
you are tuning in to please share this
live so I'm going to give you some time
before I bring my guest on I'm going to
share it too um please share this live
because it's going to be fun and there
are two other seats um in this uh in
this live so you know if there are
people that want to weigh in on the
topic later on down um the line you know
I can send you a link just send me a
private message and I'll send you a link
and then you can come on and ask my my
guest some questions but that'll be
later on um at the end of the broadcast
so um just make sure to please share
this out so I'm going to share it to my
groups hold
on um
yeah I think I'm I'm good to go um so
yeah make sure to like I said uh share
this to to whomever and uh if you want
to come in on the broadcast just let me
know in the private message and I'll
send you a link so our guest I'm just
going to read his
bio and of course I can't get out of the
screen okay so Mark profit helps leaders
solve seemingly unsolvable problems so
they um
Rel I can't look from above I am we're
gonna delete this part I'm going to edit
this
out I can't seem to get signal to come
on my just one
second yeah
sorry just one second we're going to
just plot that up again I just
can't
my no we're good I got it Mark is just
talking to me in the background here so
if you think I'm talking to myself I'm
not but uh we'll try this
again okay so Mark profit helps leaders
solve seemingly unsolvable problems so
they reliably
deliver 10 times more desired results
with less risk using readily available
resources by using predictive inov
Innovation he is a Non-Stop thinker
researcher and author and author of
predictive Innovation a first principles
based system of thinking Silicon Valley
veteran with over 30 years experience
creating new technologies including
working with apple Microsoft h h huet
Packer visa and Nintendo um at 12 at age
12 saved money from mowing lawns and
shoveling snow to buy a personal
computer and teach himself to program
began college at 14 holy Mo holy smokes
and by 16 was programming professionally
with a startup that developed the first
software to apply Edward deming's work
in uh Us automotive Factory by General
Motors wow that's
impressive dropped out of a PhD in
physics at the University of Michigan
when recruited by Apple
computer to make something insanely
great leading to the creation of the
agile
methodology while working to build the
first online crowdfunding and
peer-to-peer digital uh media platform
suffered a brain injury requiring him to
relearn how to rethink or sorry how to
think and in the process discovered how
to teach average people how to think
like a genius currently enjoys living as
a digital Nomad with a passion for
creating maker spaces to give everyone
access to tools and a community to
create GL abundance notable ACC
accomplishments um programmed the
first statistical process control system
using or sorry used in uh Us automotive
Factory contributed to creating agile
while working at Apple computer
integrated the first use of worldwide
web technology at Huer Parker at sorry
in 19
19ah I'm I'm I'm messing this up I'm
sorry
1994 um integrated the first use of
worldwide web tech oh sorry designed uh
I'm gonna have to redo this I'll
probably do this redo this in editing
so sorry I have dyslexia so sorry Mark
just it my my when I see too many too
much text I my my eyes go crazy designed
and developed the virtual virtual
reality engine used by Spectrum Hollow
on games like Top Gun and Falcon 4
oversaw technology to for the first
Global dual TV and internet video
broadcast reaching one billion uh
viewers uh taught predictive Innovation
on four continents including classes at
MIT and University
uh sorry and University of I don't know
how to pronounce
thisa Indonesia uh written two books
edited seven others produced a comedy
DVD teaching calculus appeared in a TV
commercial with Rockstar Alice Cooper
and played soccer with a baby elephant
so please give it up for Mark
profit how's it going my friend all
right sa
crap so how how how's it going it's been
it's been a while since we've been on on
on camera what what have you been up to
well I was been trying to get rid of my
house in the United States so I could
move permanently or uh make my my home
base be
Thailand so that's one of the reasons
this uh this Corona virus is a little
bit personal to me in that regard
yeah so I've been paying close attention
to it because it's uh it's spreading and
it's been spreading to Thailand more
than from other countries for various
reasons and uh I have connections to to
Asia and this is something that's going
to be a big deal or already is a big
deal and we're not hearing about it in
the United States oh uh before we get
into the uh the Corona virus uh tell us
a little bit about um pred Innovation
for those who don't understand or those
who don't know who you are well as you
mentioned uh I got hit on the head and
lost my memory and when you lose your
memory at least with the way it happened
to me it's not like you forget things
what happens is I couldn't rely on my
memory to be able to store or retrieve
things things are scrambled so as an
example of something I found myself
looking through my phone not this one it
was a flip phone at the time uh sitting
in a restaurant having to go through
through all my contacts and call
everybody on my list saying hi my name's
Mark I got hit on the head how do I know
you and at one C point I called somebody
and they said oh yeah Mark I'm your
nextdoor neighbor remember I said call
me if you have a problem well obviously
that was not going to work very well if
I couldn't remember that I knew this
person well one of the things if your if
your memory is not working uh you know
if you if you break your arm or your leg
you know uh what your what you can and
can't do and then you know when when
it's working again too right but if your
brain is broken you don't know
anything you know your brain is your
tool for
knowing so how do you know anything is
correct so this is this is a real big
problem that I was facing and I had to
uh go about solving it fortunately all
of my background was perfectly uh
organized to be doing this uh one of the
one of the things I was studying was i'
done a lot of is writing computer
languages and all computer languages and
actually all languages period follow a
certain structure they have certain key
elements these that can be broken down
into what we call First principles and
you use those to be able to make any
other language and then you can
translate between the languages because
they have these F these basic components
that all share now they might be
different in the way they way they're um
they're implemented but they have the
they have the same uh functionality in
them and I went was able to go through
this figure this out and be able to use
my brain again without relying on memory
to do it and the net effect of that is
instead of trying to remember things and
then pull it back which is I really
couldn't do very well and I still I'm
better now I'm actually quite good now
but how do I know if I'm back to normal
or not I never will right right but what
I can do now and anybody who learns this
system can do is recreate information on
demand and that sounds pretty cool in of
itself but if you can cre if you can
access information access something you
don't know anytime you want you can
access things that nobody knows on
demand you can do it predictively things
that will be known and aren't known now
and that's that's predictive Innovation
summed up pretty pretty well I know
that's kind of Broad and sort of hard
for people to picture but that's what it
it is and it allows you to do a lot of
things that would be very difficult to
do well should no impossible to do other
ways so uh like would that would
predictive Innovation be equivalent to
um what AI technology or you know like a
robot being able to pull ideas out it's
well it's exactly the opposite actually
okay robots robots are actually based on
uh what we call um deep learning or um
Big Data they're looking at at stuff
from the past memory and trying to find
patterns and then connect the patterns
predictive Innovation is the exact
opposite we have rules that apply to
absolutely everything and then we
can uh infer or deduct or um calculate
out things that to that we will know
things things that nobody knows yet it's
not relying on memory and the two worked
really well together computers are
really good at you know just Brute Force
chunking through you know grinding
through something but but predictive
Innovation can populate things that
would that you don't know yet it can
tell you the questions and where to look
and how to structure it so that you can
dis you can uh arrive at something that
no computer knows no one knows yet and
you can find it exactly when you need it
and I like to call this um real
intelligence versus artificial
intelligence and uh there's an
interesting fact which I don't know I
could explain this this is a little hard
to explain uh actually if we've got a
video here um well I I'll skip skip the
uh round square triangle demonstration
for now unless somebody asks for it
but
computers uh have to go through things
very methodically but they can do it
very very fast they don't get tired they
do it the same way what predictive
Innovation does I said first principles
we I was able to break these the all
languages or all all systems for
describing anything and predic
Innovation is a method of describing
anything that can be made or
done and I did some funky math to figure
out that this is this really can
describe anything that can be made or
done there's a mathematical proof behind
it people aren't familiar with
mathematical proofs that's very
different from evidence evidence is
something you've seen uh and it may or
may not be true because your perception
is wrong mathematical proof is something
that's been been shown by Logic to be uh
true and it's much more uh it's actually
well it's not just much more stable it
is stable uh as opposed to evidence
which may or may may not may have been
wrong to begin with maybe perceived
incorrectly it's always incomplete this
is the this is what people normally
think when they say proof they actually
mean evidence and evidence is just
statistics it's percentages of
likelihood whereas proofs are absolutes
which changes everything these are
functionally distinct they are not the
same thing they they operate in
different ways they have different uh
different impact different different
rules
altogether now in predictive Innovation
one of the key principles um from what I
understand is functional distinctions
and what is functional distinctions and
why why is why are functional
distinctions important in um in this
process well when you describe anything
you it everything that you describe has
certain characteristics about it that
make it what it
is and it's the way it operates really
defines what it is you might have heard
you know A Rose by Any Other Name still
smells as sweet well yeah it's not the
name that's it's not the name of Rose
that's the interesting point it's what a
rose actually is it's it's functionally
distinct from a
skunk you know a rose smells a certain
way it looks a certain way it it has
thorns it grows it does these certain
things that make it a rose and it's
different from a skunk it's different
from other flowers it is uh now it's
functionally shares a lot more things
with flowers or other plants it operates
the same way that's what functional
means and how it
operates and that's why we what I'm
actually looking for when I try to to
break things down into their smallest
components one way to look at this is
like the color wheel right blue yellow
and red they're they're different from
each other now they're all colors but
blue is not yellow yellow is not blue
yellow is not red they are you know
something in and of
themselves but by mixing them you can
form all the all the shades all the
colors well almost there's actually it's
not quite true because um purple is not
within those within that
realm purple is actually outside
however something that is people say
things are not uh black and white you've
heard that said before right well uh
that's actually false things are black
and
white they say things are not black and
white they're Shades of Gray well all
Shades of Gray are just mixtures of
black and white if you don't start with
black or white all you can do is have
something that's a different shade of
gray in between the outer extremes but
if you with black and white you can have
white you can have black and all of the
Shades of Gray so things really are
black and
white so when we're talking about
functional distinctions let's go through
the functional distinctions with this
outbreak um in Corona virus well
probably the first functional
distinction I'd like to make point about
the virus is it's a virus people kind of
get tripped up on this they get sick and
they they think about well I'm going go
get some antibiotics Well antibiotics
are good for bacteria and some other
things too but a virus is functionally
different from a bacteria a bacteria is
a living thing it's a living thing that
gets inside you and uh multiplies and
it's separate from your body it's
growing inside your body or on your body
and actually we have lots of bacteria
and in our system that are that are
beneficial on our system on our skin in
our stomachs you technically don't
actually digest your food the bacteria
living throughout your digestive system
uh mostly uh digest your food viruses
are very different from a bacteria
viruses aren't technically alive they
don't they don't reproduce on their own
they hijack your cells and use your
cells to reproduce themselves and
destroy the cell and then spread to
other cells and then maybe other bodies
other people or animals or whatever and
in their cells so antibiotics don't do
anything so you you can't kill a a virus
because it doesn't it's not alive
actually
it's like when it comes to viruses do
the um do these viruses attack active
cells or do they attack weak cells
or well um there's some debate about
that but your your body your has an
immune system it has an ability to get
rid of viruses or at least get rid of
the uh the cells that have been invaded
by a virus right and there's a couple
ways that it does this one way that
we're uh people frequently talk about is
antigens and if you've ever heard they
say with particularly they're talking
about now with this uh um this this
virus hold on I'm gonna sneeze
and no I am not uh I am not infected I
just have
allergies which is which is hor horrific
I've got
allergies um so uh which another reason
why I'm I it's personal because I might
not be able to get back into I might not
be able to get into Thailand because
they'll flag me saying you're sick but
yeah uh it was talking about having
vaccines uh you can't have a vaccine for
so you can have vaccine but what a
vaccine actually does is makes you
sick and this vaccine triggers your
immune system to create what are called
anti antigens antibodies that latch on
to the virus and disable
it so if you keep that in mind uh so
let's kind of step back a little bit and
give it a little more predictive
Innovation uh structure to this
we can have things that are I'm going to
give you a couple a couple of the U the
divisions of predictive Innovation
things can be the
same things are either the same or they
can be different first way things can be
different is a different type and we
already talked about that with bacteria
bacteria and viruses they're not the
same they are a different type
altogether viruses and bacteria are not
are functionally different different
type
but if we had uh say let's pick the
viruses you could have the next way
things can be the same is the same
quantity so it's the same same item same
quantity then it can be different as
long it's the same type of different
quantity you could have more or you
could have
less and those are two directions that
you can go on this uh all the way more
all the way less is the other direction
so you got same more and less between
those you have this these combinations
remember I was talking about the colors
blue and red make violet blue and uh
yellow make green well you can have
combinations same more
sameness that's the idea of uh things
stabilizing or becoming uh if you're
mathematics that's caros fenus hello
Carlos uh we have um stabilization or
asmic if you're mathematics the other
side between same and less we have less
sameness and that's uh
fluctuations vibrations uh bending and
changing and coming back so those are
these combinations and there each one of
those is functionally distinct from the
other uh less is functionally different
from more it's functionally different
from
same uh less same is functionally
different from L it's also functionally
different from same even though it's
made from the two of them and stabilize
or become is different from more it's
different from less but even though it's
made from the two of there it it
operates differently it's functionally
different and of course other in this
case other than
virus is different altogether it's
different
type and those six types or six
directions is one of is of a set of
three groups three groups of six that
can Define absolutely anything to be
made or done these are how you can put
things together and I probably just lost
everybody with this
but I'm sitting here at this maker space
and we have
tools and these tools all tools operate
the same way actually everything
operates this way we've got some tools
that remove material a saw a drill um
that over there that orange thing is a
laser it's big
laser okay it burns or Cuts
something so a lot of tools remove but
we also have tools that add things
together they can weld we can uh uh put
bolts screws
um uh attach things in various ways so
it's adding things together we can uh
keep things the same uh masking tape uh
a vice to hold things in place another
type of sameness is to measure something
it doesn't change but we're measuring
we're looking at is it the same is it
different how much is it how is it
different and every tool that you go
through in this maker space which is
huge building has has operates in one of
these six different
ways and that's that's true with
absolutely any tool or
anything that
exists so you would be able to oh sorry
I don't mean to interrupt but um you
would be able to just you could look at
something with predictive Innovation
You' be able to decode where it where it
where it falls on one of those
directions yeah and actually we're
literally having
boxes um yeah so those the
directions we've got it on the screen
the in them Center there it's it's same
above that is other or you know not same
different
uh more less and then the the
combinations of the two in between there
so it's not just that I can uh say what
they they are but these describe uh six
uh columns is how I usually use it in a
in a grid or so we got six boxes across
got six more and we end up with 36 boxes
and each one of those
boxes is a dysfunctionally distinct type
that maybe there's well there will be
something in that box maybe we know it
maybe we don't but I can describe it
well enough that I can go looking for it
or maybe make it even if it doesn't
exist and that gets back to what I was
saying about knowing stuff that you
don't know if you can describe it well
enough you can make it even if no one
else even if the technology currently
doesn't exist you can at least describe
how it will be made when the technology
enables you to do that so you can
predict
things so would you be able to
predict uh how to combat this
virus yeah absolutely so so there's some
things that you could do with combating
the virus and we already talked about
how people are looking at some of these
ways one way would be a vaccine right
well uh unfortunately vaccine's not a
really good way of doing this because
you have to know what the vaccine you
have to know what the virus is
first yeah and uh then you have to uh be
able
to develop uh normally way viruses work
is they make you sick so you have to
somehow make somebody sick without
killing them this current Corona virus
kills people uh at least that's what it
seems to be going on and it and uh which
is unlike the flu they keep here in the
United States they talk about oh well
the flu kills so many people flu doesn't
kill anybody it's the side effects the
uh of having the flu that leads people
to die you get this flu that cause you
to be sick and then something else uh
you die from because you you had the flu
this thing actually gives you pneumonia
and you
die very different functionally distinct
from you got sick and because you got
sick you know you died from that you
know um you know you you don't you don't
you never die from getting stabbed or
very rarely to people getting die from
being stabbed they die from bleeding
from being stabbed
right right uh you don't die from
falling you die from hitting the
ground you know you know that's cute
little joke on this is uh this guy
jumped out of the the Empire State
Building and he's racing down and passes
the guy on the 45th floor and he says
how's it going he goes so good so
far yeah
funny but it's sad at the same time but
you know what that's yeah yeah anyway
the end that's that's the problem yeah
for sure well so this um so vaccines are
kind of inherently
dangerous if they you can have a a one
way you can do this is again so positive
negative right so this is kind of basing
where we're using an other or a negative
approach on this we're going to make you
sick so that your body figures out how
to become how to overcome this thing and
kill
it anti anti bacterias or antibacterials
or an um
antibiotics try to kill the thing again
a negative approach but fundamentally
what you really are what even in the
vaccine is doing is letting your immune
system take care of you so you'd be way
better off to have your immune system
strong enough to take care of you uh
from the
beginning but uh and there's a way to
actually do U that this with sort of a
vaccine approach but again it's not that
great for this particular situation but
that would be and they do this sometimes
they take they take the infection the
infective agent the the
virus uh put it in some sort of cells
and uh create the antigens and instead
of giving you a weakened irus to cause
your body to create the antigens they
just give you the
antigens Which is less
risky but again the problem with this is
you need to have identified this thing
and then it takes time to go through
this see if you've weakened it enough
see if you're once it's weakened
somebody's body creates antigens
recognizes it and then it it hasn't
hopefully hasn't changed in the interim
we're talking at least three months out
well this this particular particular
virus seems to spread uh uh it can
within 14 days it can go from one person
to making the person deathly ill and
then maybe dead another five days later
uh we don't have three months to screw
around right so we we need a different
approach so let's look the other
direction let's look at a different type
let's keep people one thing we could do
is we can make people we could try to
recover which again sort of not the best
best way to go right uh get back this
fluctuate start off bad and return well
we could try to heal the people after
the fact probably not the best best
approach if we can choose not to but
sometimes that's all we can
do keeping them keeping them healthy or
making them more healthy if you could
make people more healthy that's the
better option all
around we'll get we'll get into that in
a little second let's put that on
because that seems a little hard to
believe but we could easily keep people
healthy so now we're talking about the
scales you can keep one person one
person healthy some people healthy many
people healthy anyone healthy everyone
healthy or no one healthy and you notice
I it's counted to six one yeah many and
I don't know if you've got
the the there yeah so
again it takes the same format as the
the
directions yeah have some I've got a
somebody here with me at the maker space
he's using a 3D printer right now which
is worries which is additive um additive
manufacturing you you add the stuff
together I've got two pounds of
pistachios and they were on sale so I
was I bought a lot I love pistachios
so keep people healthy well the easiest
way to keep people healthy is to keep
the VAC the the virus away from
them and that's actually we could we
could do it by uh killing the virus
again that's a negative but you can use
uh
alcohol this particular virus uh is not
particularly um uh chlorine uh bleach
doesn't kill it very well you have to
use a really high concentration of of
bleach to kill it but alcohol Works
quite works pretty well uh vinegar
actually works which is
interesting
um uh interesting yeah it is interesting
uh there's some other things that work
pretty well as also but uh just
basically cleaning uh works and this is
we talking different types right this is
a alcohol poisons it it also it also has
a mechanical effect but
soap uh kills different things it
doesn't actually kill a virus because
viruses don't actually live but it tears
them
apart it's the same way that it takes
your oils apart off your skin it it's a
surfacant it connects to them and tears
it apart well if it tears it apart they
break up doesn't work anymore it can't
infect you we can try to approach that
way we can uh try to just prevent it
from getting your body if it doesn't get
in your body through your no through
mucous membranes your nose your mouth
your eyes
um any of your other orifices if you
can't get
in you don't get
sick and one of the things we're seeing
with this this disease here is people
wear U uh surgical masks real cheap sort
of piece of fabric acrosser mouth that
is completely useless H it's not
completely useless but it's almost use
completely useless for preventing you
from getting sick right right but if
everybody
was to wear one of those those work
really well preventing you from making
other people
sick and remember I said this disease
can take uh up to 14 days before you get
sick and then if you do you're you know
you'll be dead in five more days so
within 30 days if if everybody if
everybody wore a surgical mask for 30
days and wash their hands and such this
diseas to be
gone so that one more
time if if so the the concept is this if
nobody spreads it to anybody
else it goes
away that's true because it doesn't live
it's not like it's crawling on the floor
to look for another host it's right it
well that there's another issue it could
be coming from another host which was
probably what we which the the guess is
that's where it came from to begin with
but uh but as far as right now we could
prevent people from spreading it to each
other
wearing a a normal surgical mask just
something over your mouth to keep you
from coughing on other
people and washing your hands so you
don't leave your nastiness on things for
other people to touch and get in their
eyes and rubb their face if you just did
that for 30 days this would probably be
gone it would just
disappear do you think because I know
that with this virus coming out of China
um you know the Chinese have
you know they eat certain types of foods
that I don't think that's the biggest
issue I know a lot of people talked
about that being the issue eating bats
eating eating uh snakes and this and
that that's that's I mean that could be
that could be what happened I wouldn't
look at it that way but let's say it is
so we've got we've got these different
different things that uh that have their
viruses and their back and their
bacteria that live inside them and when
we get if we were to get one from from a
bat particularly bat would be one I'd be
concerned about I would be less I would
not suspect a snake as much because
snake is functionally different bats are
mammals you know they're
warm-blooded hairy animals just like
people they're the same type
functionally similar so they would be
more likely to have something that could
be transmitted to a human than than a
snake snakes are cold blooded they're
they're very different in the way they
they operate the snakes having viruses
that could live in a human seems a
little far-fetched to me but bats yeah
uh and actually one thing uh that we
know about is pigs pigs have lots of
lots of things that they share with us
we even sometimes take pigs Pig organs
and Transplant them to humans human
hearts if you need a heart transplant if
one of the first transplants was
actually a pig heart because you could
put that into a into a human and it
would
work so uh if if you if you're so
inclined to think this way it's probably
a good idea don't eat pork because and I
don't when I'm in Asia I don't eat pork
um mostly because I know that they don't
have and this is actually more the issue
they they don't use refrigeration and
they don't have prop really good
sanitation and I don't want to be
bringing into my you know uh into my
system something that it may carry uh a
disease that's would be really
comfortable inside me
right right because you know when you're
eating food like that what especially it
doesn't matter any type of meat you're
going your body your stomach is going to
produce acid to break that down if you
if your if your body is constantly
producing acid it's going to break down
those mucous membranes that protect your
cells so no uh the acid's in your
stomach
it's the path between your mouth and and
your stomach that you got to worry about
it and it's also the path up your nose
and actually the biggest problem you
possibly have is breaking your skin if
you get a cut it could be very small an
abrasion a rash and you get stuff going
into your skin that goes into your
bloodstream that's what you got to worry
about that's the biggest issue that you
need to worry about uh and that's and
again cover that up protect that keep
the things out so keep
stable uh that's the the best thing you
could possibly do is prevent things from
getting into your body uh rather than
trying to deal with it after the fact or
trying to kill everything that's out
there in the world well you can't do
that it's just just too much stuff right
I me you you can kill a lot of things
and uh one of the things I do right now
and I'm think I've been playing with
this at my own my house here in the
United States uh and seeing about maybe
I'm GNA do this before I go back to
Thailand is I've got an ozone
generator which uh generates a gas
called ozone which is actually just
oxygen it takes oxygen electrically
stimulates it treats it turning it into
O3 instead of o2 we breathe O2 O3 is
highly reactive and it's uh it
essentially makes anything that comes in
contact with
rust uh but liting things viruses fungi
anything it will technically rust and uh
it's a gas so it fills all the cracks
and goes into places where you can't rub
with a nice you can't wash down and I
can run this thing and uh
completely sterilize sterilize yeah the
whole the whole whole place clothing
whatever the whole
building which is which is an attack
type of thing and it's very broad
spectrum doesn't kill everything I mean
it's it's ozone's pretty nasty but it's
not uh it's not the nastiest thing in
the world but it's works pretty darn
well and it's a gas so that's a we think
it's continuous say single so we could
have uh single
multiple uh or you know partial uh
multiple and the continuous types any
all none so a gas can go all all areas
it expands out it fills whatever it's in
it could go anywhere within within the
boundaries as opposed to say like
alcohol spray alcohol it stays on on the
surface alcohol is a liquid so it can go
it can divide it up it can spread over
but it stays in it's it's much more
limited in the way that it functions
than right a gas and of course it's also
much more limited than say something uh
if you just scrub it if you just rub
something off which is very phys you
know physical uh which you might think
of as a multiple or a or a single
uh option but that's probably a bad
example to explain to people on that one
I'll try to come up with a better one no
worries so but yeah there's so there's
you can look at these diseases and look
at how you kill it that way keep it keep
it out so that's what I was saying about
the the face mask if everybody
continuous wore a face mask to keep
their own diseases
inside they won't transmit to any other
people
so then only the people who currently
have them will suffer and everybody else
will be
fine and you can actually apply that to
a lot of diseases the um the the quote
AIDS epidemic well if nobody gives
anybody else AIDS which is actually
really hard to
do I mean you have really have to go out
of your way to try to transmit that
disease uh right it could be eliminated
in one generation just gone nobody ever
has it ever again same same kind of
concept there's a lot of things that
fall under that that wh if you don't if
you don't replicate it it goes away but
that you know sounds great in a perfect
world but you know in our world we tend
to make a lot of mistakes and you know
and something just as wearing a
mask people don't want to do or you know
people have Mis you know they'll have
their own misconceptions or they don't
really have the they don't really have
the right idea of what the problem is so
they can't remed remedy it so exactly so
that's why I said all
so what we just described here is so you
said a yes but yes absolutely this
works yeah
but a whole bunch of problems right
we've got uh you know people don't know
uh they they might do it wrong uh they
might not have the material materals
actually everybody has the materials
everybody could have the materials to do
this but it's mostly information problem
at that
point um so anytime you you have a
problem that's structured in that that
format of yes but that seems like a
seemingly unsolvable problem I'd like
this but I can't because of that it's a
you know chicken and egg Catch 22 uh we
call it a
dilemma yeah that seeming unsolvable
problem is actually the easiest problem
to to
solve and it's really simple on how you
do it you take each
word and you flip it say not to that
word
so people uh so they know or they uh not
know okay not no well something that's
other than no or the opposite instead of
knowing well doing is not knowing do
they need to know or do they just need
to
do you could have somebody just forcing
people to do the right thing or you
could give them something that forces
them to do the right thing um I actually
ran into a switching the subject a
little bit but I was into McDonald's
just
recently and uh had one of these
problems these yes but problems uh it
took I put my order in and didn't
realize that they were still working on
two orders before me and 22 minutes
later they still didn't get my ordered
done and I'm wondering what the heck's
going on because it was an automated
McDonald's I they didn't I didn't they
didn't even have to take my order I put
my order
in yeah I I I I wanted a burger fries
and a drink 22 minutes later I still
don't have a burger fries and a drink
and one of the employees comes up to me
and goes what are you waiting for and
I'm thinking to myself why is she asking
me it's up on the screen back there I
can see it on their screen right and it
hit
me I doubt that anybody in that that
McDonald's could
read and they had
to uh had to ask me to tell this person
and then that person would tell the
person working the next thing to work on
because I couldn't memorize all of it
for every person and they we have to do
it one at a time remember what I was
saying about memory and not being able
to do
things uh reading is a tool it's a
technique for not relying on your
memory
well we already tried to have these
people be able to read right no and that
failed um in Detroit the 87 I think it's
about I think the number is 87 87% of
the people who graduate from uh from
schools the the government schools what
we call public schools in uh Detroit are
uh illiterate functionally illiterate
they can't
read so how could you is there a way
that you could actually make this work
uh yeah there there is how about this we
are everything else is already automated
at that
restaurant but it is helpful to have you
know hands just how about if the
screen had uh place where had symbols
you could press on the symbol and it
would then have their headset tell them
what that thing
is they click on it say all right that's
what you're supposed to work on now it
says I'm know uh Bob is working on that
and they can do that so they can have
the machine read to them that's
perfectly available technology we have
right now and we could have it do that
they still get the they still have the
job they're still working on it
and it keeps that organization going on
without having somebody having to talk
to the customer to tell them what's
going on they can act more
independently so we could actually do
that uh that's a a a yes but they can't
read so they can't follow the
instructions they can't operate on their
own uh but they don't need to read they
just need to know what's next what's
next yeah not read know what
next and we can do that multiple ways
and one of the things I said on this
functional distinctions is instead of
reading instead of using your eyes let's
use their
ears seeing is different from hearing
and they could understand that now if
you can hear you could you could do
different languages as well you if
you're G to have the text come in we
already have Google translate and things
this uh uh Google translate does this or
we could record uh have these you know
you know press one if you want Spanish
press two if you want English press
three if you want
H yeah onay that's
Russian that's Russian for I don't
understand yeah for
sure so that would be a fairly easy
technology that could be implemented to
solve that problem and it's really just
the way I got to that solution is not I
said not not read okay not read well
okay what else could they do beside read
well how about not eyes all right fine
they were talking let's do that they
could do that we could we could have it
do that um and then unfortunately the
the the the net effect is if you've got
too much automation going this replacing
the person not person comes along very
quickly after this right and it seems to
be something that will be coming down
the pipeline pretty soon at uh
McDonald's yes yes uh and one of the
things I was thinking of while I was at
to McDonald's though was this we've got
people that can't
read handling
food and if they can't read then they
probably aren't aware of a virus that's
spreading around the world that can kill
people uh are they going to pay
attention to you know the instructions
to W to clean their hands to wear a mask
they should be wearing face masks in
that cough on the food to not you know
to wash their hands before they go to
the bathroom and this and that and I'm
thinking uh I
would actually prefer to not have a
human anywhere near my
food well yeah you know but then it goes
back to what I was saying earlier you
know I guess what you called a dilemma
but I mean people are people they will
follow the directions and they will make
mistakes and you know that's why we'll
have we'll continue to have problems
when it comes to this virus do you know
about the SARS virus and how they were
able
to um I think I don't I don't recall and
again that's having to know something uh
and I don't don't recall I don't know if
I ever heard very much about it from
what I remember is it mostly just wore
itself out it wasn't that
bad that's what I recall maybe somebody
else knows better than than me we can
look we can look that up well let's see
if there's anyone I'm just gonna just
one second I just uh a buzzer went off
upstairs just one second I'll be right
back all right well I'm gonna finish
talking about this go ahead come back
so one of the things uh that I was just
mentioning about that is you should have
muted your microphone before getting up
and doing
that we're gonna find out now that he's
not actually uh going upstairs because a
buzzer went off we're going to find out
that there's somebody in other room and
he's start yelling at them and he
doesn't know that this is what I'm
saying but he'll find this out later and
we'll get to hear them yelling at each
other well we you can have a complete
system right everybody wears the masks
well that would be ideal but we can't
that's un that's
unlikely well what about uh dividing it
up having some people wear
masks how about
if we do more than just doing the masks
if we do other things multiple
things well let's use the same technique
of preventing the disease from spreading
to people but do it in different
ways putting masks on everybody would do
this keeping people away from each other
would do it
also a quarantine does this and
technically that's what I'm saying by
putting a a mask on your
face you're self-quarantining yourself
you are putting this barrier between you
and other people you're putting yourself
into a quarantine and if everyone
quarantined themselves problem would go
away
completely is that required well no in
the physical world we don't need 100%
typically because not everybody has the
disease not everybody will die from
having the disease not everyone will
catch the disease even if they're
exposed to it what we need is to just
get it enough
so that it does so that the transmission
rates are less than the Cure rates and
it will go away too so that's this
percentage or partial uh solution
instead of an an any or an all solution
we can get it to effectively go
away by using a different technique and
we can really actually get all of these
uh by using any one of the solutions the
ution types the 36 types the more a
single more partial more multiple more
any more no all more no none more and
then less
opposite I called
it well he's not yelling he said you
should you should have muted your
microphone before going off and banging
around sorry I didn't realize I did did
do that that's okay you uh the audience
had uh we we we took
a we we had laughter at your expense oh
no oh yeah there's my the rice cooker uh
went off and it burns the U like I put
quinoa in it and burns the quinoa so I
had to run up there and just make sure
that it
did that's interesting yeah that's I
wonder why it burns quinoa
um it shouldn't burn
anything yeah you leave it on for you
know for a certain period of time and
then it'll it'll just burn the bottom ah
ah okay I was just recently watched a
video you notice that the rice cookers
how they work they you put them in there
it cooks and just suddenly stops right
right there's a magnet in the bottom of
that
oh and the magnet keeps the switch on
and when magnets get hot they lose their
magnet their their magnetic attraction
so when it gets to a certain temperature
it which be just about boiling point it
becomes UNM magnetic and
stops and turns
off so that's super cool yeah and I bet
yours ALS has a standby on there so it
doesn't just turn off it switches over
it goes to warm to warm yeah yeah uh
mine doesn't do that but what I do
instead and I learned this when I was in
Panama of all places I was trying to
cook some rice and I was trying to
cooking over a propane stove with a pan
and we it wasn't working uh and my
friend's Panamanian and I'm cooking rice
and I was at this hostel an upscale nice
hostel not one of the ones that um
typical Backpackers
stay at but uh I couldn't figure out we
couldn't figure out how to make rice and
we felt really stupid not being able to
cook rice and uh this woman from Japan
comes in she's Tokyo she goes put in the
microwave and we both like what
huh microwave but I mean I'm not arguing
with someone from Tokyo about
rice yeah and and it hit me I like well
wait a minute that is brilliant
microwaves
vibrate
fluctuate uh
water they primarily heat water they got
a wider range they'll heat other thefts
but primarily they heat W water so you
put the rice with the water in there
they will boil it'll boil the water
until the water's
gone and it'll it'll essentially stop
cooking even if you leave it on a little
too
long oh cool yes so you always get
perfect rice if you microwave it yeah
wow I didn't know that well so back to
the virus we were talking about um we
talked about the functional distinctions
we talked about the
different types of solutions we've
talked about
dilemas uh and how to use um in your
inverting words to yeah we we danced
around the inversion a little bit we
didn't get into full of it but yeah you
can take each every single word in the
sentence and invert it flip it so not
the person not read not know uh not do
so knowing instead of doing not the
person well you could have uh a machine
you could have uh the system that does
it you could have a non-person do it you
know a dog a a plant different things
and every single word in the sentence
can be flipped like that so typically
you got about 22 words in any one of
these
if uh yes
but uh types of dilemmas so there at
least 22 different solutions to
something that you thought had zero and
if you know about math if you've got
this or that
two to for 22 things that's two to the
power of 22 which is a big
number it's about uh I think it's about
300,000 I think is what the that that is
combinations of
solutions let me just do this just to be
say two to the power
of 22 oh 4 million sorry 4,
1994 wow thousand so four four 4.2
million combinations of solutions when
you thought there was zero to start with
wow now let's get to China and some of
the things that I've been seeing um
quite repetitively is that people are
saying that China is
reporting false statistics false news in
regards to the
um in regards to the the virus like what
are your thoughts on that well what I my
I've got my thoughts and then what I've
heard now uh my thoughts are based on my
information and based on me doing some
logic to try to figure this out yeah and
what I've heard is experiential right I
about memory somebody told me this and
maybe it's true maybe it's not I've been
hearing the same thing I've been hearing
that it's much bigger than what they're
reporting they say there's about 4,000
people have it uh I've heard people say
as much as 10 times that uh I've heard
the number of
90,000 tossed around yeah what's true
can we actually know something about it
uh could actually make a fairly good
guess at some things about this and have
a general and take that General system
and apply it to other stuff by the
way so we know from experience that the
Chinese government tends to FIB about
these things there's a thing in Asia
called face or Saving Face we even have
that you know in in America in the
western world but not the way they do it
there they've they want to make sure
that China looks good the the government
looks good there's no uh there's no
chance of anybody being uh overthrowing
the government so they like to really
clamp down on any negative things that
come out well yeah one thing we has come
out they've told about they've bragged
about it is that they're rushing to
build a hospital in six days in the city
where this came
out that seems a little odd why do they
need a hospital if you got 4,000 people
sick
you know can't you just put in hospitals
another thing that they did which
they've talked about so we could trust
them at least you know we can trust them
when they say negative stuff because we
know that they tend not that they don't
want to say negative stuff they
quarantined the whole city 50 million
people have been
quarantined now does that sound like a
mild thing if you've got 4,000 people
sick would you lock up 50 million
people it seems like a fairly extreme
response to the conditions they're
telling us they
have and they said they've got like 100
120 deaths so far four million people
sick 12 deaths lock up 50 million
people yeah the math doesn't make sense
yeah it doesn't make sense so that alone
makes you think that yeah maybe this is
not what it's not going the way they
that they're saying and that's that
technique now let's take that and apply
to something else apply that technique
to to you know what people say versus
what they
do uh and I'll get a little political on
this but this is a good example Al Gore
talks about or Greta Greta
thorberg talks about the world's going
to end in however long
right by 2050 by 2050 hour you know 12
years 12 years it's all going to die
we're all going to die yet the clintons
and gors and stuff bu Land by property
byy huge mansions Oceanfront
mansions that does not sound like
somebody who believes that by putting
out any more carbon dioxide the world's
going to end they fly around on private
jets that does not sound like somebody
who actually believes that they need to
stop their carbon emissions
so that should make your question if
these people who are very vigorous about
saying these things are not acting like
they believe their own things they're
saying maybe they're lying to themselves
or or you or both
right and you could you could take this
take that same technique for
anything hi
Anthony so that that that technique
there of uh and that's one of the that's
one of the first steps when you do the
inversion uh technique first thing we do
is we check our assumptions is this
true if it's not true do something
else you know the problem problem's not
not real don't worry about it move on
for sure yeah and but what we need to do
though is figure out a way to test to
see if it's true or not which is
actually what they're doing this this
this virus right now uh when somebody
shows up do they have the disease well
this is actually one of the problems
about this disease is actually
supposedly what we believe is this
disease you have you're
asymptomatic meaning you don't show
symptoms for up to 14
days and you could be transmitting it
now that's not been
confirmed but if that's the case this is
really bad
have somebody wandering around for 14
days being Typhoid Mary spreading this
to you know everybody they come in
contact with right and then getting sick
and everybody behind them getting sick
14 days later right uh that's really bad
because uh well let's let's just let's
just do that do the math on that one
really which is something people don't
tend to avoid but you could do the math
on this if you've got if you just infect
one person every day for 14 days that's
people wow right it it compounds pretty
quickly right yes it does you you come
into if you're going to work for example
and uh you you're coming in contact with
at least a 100 people if you're living
in China especially you're taking the
bus this the train if your job involves
uh Food Service particularly over there
or you go to the wet market and this is
why we kind of got off the wet Market we
I was going to say the wet markets
themselves are actually a problem uh for
for disease issues it's not so much that
the bat that they're eating bats
and zika zika how are you doing my
friend so it's not that it's I mean yes
eating bats probably not a good idea
because you can catch stuff from bats
that you wouldn't catch from other
things eating snakes probably not quite
as bad but uh some reasons to not eat
snakes mostly because snakes eat things
that catch diseases that we should
there's a there's a kind of basic rule
you should apply don't eat things that
that are scavengers or eat eat
pests you want to avoid those
U other than chickens for some reason
chickens are
horrible but they're they're Birds oh
yeah chicken chickens Le all kinds of
nasty
stuff I didn't know that yeah they're
they're pretty they're pretty awful um
we typically don't feed them that stuff
but they they
do but I I honestly didn't know that
yeah but but chickens are chickens
they're birds so we we don't catch
things from from Birds because they're
not they're not similar enough to us so
they don't so the diseases don't build
up in chickens for us to catch uh
however you can get things like
salmonella which is actually not
technically from the chicken it's
actually on the chicken and if you cook
the chicken and clean the chicken you
won't get it it's good reason to not eat
never eat hamburger yeah Anthony says
you can become batty by eating
bats yep so far we don't know that it's
actually bats but we do know you can
become baddy from eating bad uh from
from cows that eat
cows and that's prion
disease uh you know yeah which is a
different thing
altogether um yeah the Mad Cow mad
cow which by the way prons are not a
bacteria they're not a virus they're
also not
alive they're they're a a little bizarre
I think they're a protein and anyways
they they get into things and they just
drill holes in your brain tissue and
it's nasty so functionally different and
you have to treat them differently you
have to really cook the crap out I mean
actually it's almost Beyond cooking uh
actually it is beyond cooking you you
have to just basically disintegrate
whatever it is to get rid of them
they're really prons are hard to get rid
of and so don't cannibalism is bad
[Laughter]
okay yes it's
bad yeah even for
cows yeah no you're
spiders yeah also know your
spiders yeah so I kind of got off an a
attention there but oh yeah yeah so so
you a wet Market most of you here in the
United States we don't know about wet
markets uh a wet Market you have all
kinds of meats and fish and
unfortunately also produce sitting out
uh on just on tables uh they have live
animals there H you can go get a chicken
and you could say that chicken there the
one that's wanding around I want to eat
that one and they will grab that chicken
slit its throat drain the Blood Out
pluck it cut it up and give it give it
back to you all the all that stuff
including sometimes they give you a
little little uh baggie full of the
blood so that you can cook with cook
things with that and all this stuff is
all over the place and you've got this
open air with raw meat and animals and
all kinds of different raw meats and you
can get things on all all of these
things that You' have to try to clean
off and that's really hard to do plus
you got all the people wandering around
coughing on things this and that it's
really
unsanitary especially from our
perspective uh it's it's not uh there
they do some other stuff that we would
were a little shocked about that is not
quite as bad as what we think it is but
those are bad and especially in China
because in China they're they don't tend
to wash their hands very well uh if they
just washed their hands and avoided
coughing on stuff this wouldn't be that
horrible but they don't they don't do
that they don't wash their hands they
you know handle money they chop stuff up
on the
ground this is nasty they have all the
Blood and Guts and stuff on the ground
and they s wash it away so just Dr down
the drain so this is just a incredibly
good environment for uh having diseases
fester and build up
and get to a certain level that they can
infect people and there's a functional
distinction right there
uh I talked about functional distinction
of type versus amount well sometimes
amount is functionally different from
type if uh you if you have a low enough
bacterial level so not talking viruses
bacteria your body can over can take
care of it you have to get it high
enough for it to really affect you or
you have to have it high enough that
that you encounter enough of it to get
infected well this is ex exactly the
environments for it it's hot it's wet
it's got all sorts you know blood serum
and feces
and crazy animals from all over the
place and all kind things this is just
bad this is not what you want for for
health so you know in in these uh you
call them cold markets wet markets wet
markets so in the wet markets if you
have all these disease kind of passing
hands and on um meats and stuff like
that are people inhaling the Aromas off
the meat and getting sick or they yes
sometimes they stink yes yes yes you you
you're inhaling all this stuff exactly
so if there's anything that's Airborne
or it's even there's there's two
different kinds of Airborne by the
way oh Roberta's super sick well I'm oh
no
Roberta and folks um feel free to if you
guys want to come up uh you if Mark
doesn't mind uh uh if you guys want to
come into the uh the podcast then I will
I can send you a link but you know it's
up to my guest here oh that'd be great
to we can have somebody come in and sort
of a question question answers what you
suggest earlier yeah Anthony what you're
describing I think is actually uh the
Philippines they call it
balute which is uh you have an egg a
fertilized egg
and duck egg typically and you wait a
certain number of days before it's grown
that much and then they boil it inside
the inside the shell and you crack it
open and eat it so it's basically just
eating duck or chicken or whatever uh
it's uh it's the whole it's eat whole
and it's
um it's uh you know that's basically
what it is it's not quite as bad as what
it sounds but there's no way I'm eating
it okay because it's
you know the the bones are on the
hopefully you know if they get at the
right time they're not crunchy they're
just kind of squishy but and the
feathers aren't grown in yet they're
just pined feathers so there's that and
this but yeah it seems a little nasty
and of course it was uh they you know
you boiled it to death that's what you
did because it was living thing inside
there but that's ballut and there's uh
yeah they have it in Thailand they
definitely have it in China uh
so yeah you're you're welcome we're I'm
guessing she was facius though what it
was were you being honest or factious
there Roberta uh she's pretty honest
okay yeah CA she said that she said that
what was I was describing balut which is
nasty yeah no but she's she has a lot of
gratitude um you know she expresses a
lot of gratitude so well thank you yeah
you
got so
what what do we do now okay so as I had
said when you were away the the want
ultimate solution we if we had some way
of just giving you know treating
everybody and they get better that would
be fabulous we don't we won't that's not
going to work okay so that's one type we
want but that's outside of our Bears so
let's try a different kind we could if
everyone we masks then self uh
quarantined but probably can't pull that
one off but could we do a partial of
that yes we could we could have some
people quarantine
themselves and if you have a and because
not everybody will get sick some
people's immune systems are good enough
uh not everybody is sick already so they
don't actually have to quarantine
themselves and uh some people even if
they do get sick will get better we
don't have to have 100% in order to have
it be effective we can even have it
enough so that uh all we really have to
do is have it uh enough people not
getting it in Rel relation to the people
that get it that it'll eventually die
off you know that obviously in that the
number I just said there you're GNA have
people get sick and die but it can come
under control as long as you know the
number of people getting it is less than
the number of people getting over it it
will go away eventually and I think
that's basically what happened with SARS
and Mera MCA was really bad uh middle
Easter
respiratory uh syndrome it killed people
too really
quickly but we could also do some other
things on on this uh you could have uh
we could have a partial we have partial
solution quarantines we could have
physical quarantines which technically
is what you're putting the mask in front
of you but they quarantine the city
China blocked off an entire city 50
million people they're locked in they're
not allowed to go to leave the city uh
that's not working great by the way at
least 5 million people left the city
before they knew how many people
actually had the stuff so it spread and
they've already detected it spread but
uh we can stop people from coming to
your country uh the Thailand has not
done that or did not do that effectively
which is one of the reasons that
Thailand has more people uh infected
other than China than any other place
also it's because a lot of Chinese went
go to Thailand Thailand's a
vacation tourist destination the
Philippines though uh and this gets into
we were talking about governments and
you're asking me how do I know that or
why do I believe that they're lying
about the numbers well the system is in
play how they operate tells you what
they will do uh dorte is President of
the Philippines well people complain
about dorte being a dictator and he's
quasi dictator he's not exactly but he's
he's a good he's fairly close close on
this well if you've got a good dictator
as opposed to a bad dictator like in in
China that's the most efficient thing
you can possibly have dorte said no
Chinese come in boom they're they're
banned no visa on arrival they can't
come in problem
solved they are qu they are quarantined
away from the Philippines at least now
is that 100% probably not because you
get some Filipinos or somebody else some
ties or somebody else maybe in the
future who come in they don't want
but that's a really good solution for
for them uh Mongolia did the same thing
no Chinese we're not allowed just not
allowed the US hasn't done that yet
we've keep having cases pop up around
the United States Canada's had cases
Germany's had cases uh France has got
cases they're starting to pop up all
over the place um because there people
are and so far has only been people from
China so what about I don't mean to
interrupt but what about uh
products that we that we use that come
from China I mean there was a uh for
example there was a lady that was on my
Facebook and she' made an announcement
that they can't manufacture any Goods
for the next two weeks well that's an
interesting problem so let's say that
that Corona virus was not deadly okay
yeah it just made people sick but it
made a lot of people sick because that's
kind of what the how the numbers work
you know if you can infect 14 people
and it's just a bad disease uh you know
if you get 20 million people sick you
can't make your
products that's going to be a big impact
economically you're gonna have things
that can't be can't be made and it'll be
difficult to move the M making to
someplace else also yeah because uh and
now this is actually an interesting
point where we think about this if we're
going to plan something predication wise
we have
one often there's what we call a you
know economies a scale if we do enough
of something uh then we'll get it'll get
cheaper so we build one the and when
economies and scale come into place
basic what basically what that means is
you've got some fixed cost you in order
to get the first one you have to spend a
lot of money on maybe tools to get the
get the tools to get a a tool that can
do it really fast and really cheap you
got to spend a lot of money to build
that tool this this machine but then
after that you can build them really
really quick really cheap but when
something goes wrong you're building
none and that's the most expensive thing
you could possibly have now you've got
this machine not working you spent the
money on it and you're not getting your
profits or at least revenue from selling
it you're spending M you spent money and
you're spending money and you're losing
potential money because you're doing
nothing so a better approach is to be
able to
maybe possibly give up some of that
productivity for uh security so have
multiple machines that can do it or have
multiple locations that can that can do
this build some of it in in China build
some of it in Vietnam build some in
Thailand build some in Mexico other
places even if you could very rapidly uh
put up a now this gets closer to any if
you could rapidly uh put up a uh a
factory in the United States
even if you don't ever intend to use the
factory in the United States but if you
could quickly do it and it's more
expensive let's just say that it'll be
more expensive to do in the China there
but if you can do it on instantly when
you need it that saves you from losing
all the money of not having it at all
and you just use that worst case
scenario this is a an any type of
solution so you know single multiple
continuous any or all all would be a
very different solution altogether let's
say that any one can make build it you
provide the information you use Simple
tools that everybody has you don't need
to have these factories that you put
together we we already have things of
this nature and actually maker space is
kind of trying to push us into that I'm
trying to make that possible where uh
he's got a 3D printer over there he can
you can download the designs and 3D
print it something you could do that
somewh with the laser cutter over there
uh where the the the tools and because
it's the maker space he you don't have
to own these tools you can use them by
having a membership this lowers that
that threshold so anybody can do it uh
and or everybody can do it we have our
phones everybody has a cell phone these
days so everybody can record video
Everybody Can record audio everybody can
talk to everybody
else uh where it used to be there was
only a very s there was at one time only
one person that was able to do it there
and then a very select group of people a
few types of people then there was some
duplication and then it got now where
it's any all and that's where we're at I
a question over here so yeah just one
second let me uh BR says what can I do
to heal I'm concerned I have bad asthma
and now with this um Corona
virus I'm freaking out well first off
well first off where are you
she's in Calgary Alberta she lives in my
city okay uh Calgary Alberta is seem
right now quite a distance away from
anybody else that has Corona virus it's
also a very low um uh low population
area so diseases won't spread very
readily out there so you're in good
shape in that as far as that's concerned
you are closer to to one of the cases
though and a place where cases are going
to come from unfortunately um you got
Seattle over there you've got a lot of
Chinese living there and then across the
border from Seattle or in
Oregon or sorry Seattle up there uh so
be aware of it so avoid it that's one of
the first thing I'd say stay healthy
don't get
it um as far as your asthma's concerned
though uh uh are you do you actually I
mean asthma asthma's an interesting
thing this is functional distinction
problem they say
asthma but asthma is a condition
typically
not a cause what causes the asthma
asthma is more you know my lungs are
inflamed my whatever I can't breathe but
there's but the cause of the asthma is
not
identified is that's the
case I live in the most populated area
of Chinese of and Calgary okay
uh but I mean it's not that people are
traveling in and out of uh China and
then going directly into your
neighborhood um but I mean we do have
don't Chinese buffet that's the first
thing I would do don't do
that which sounds bizarre but don't eat
a buffets definitely don't eat a Chinese
buffet
that that will drastically reduce your
chances of catching
something just basic numbers this if
it's only coming from people from China
right now the only people you would have
to have somebody who came from China or
went to China and came back happened to
have caught it and came back and then
transmitted it to what to you
somehow you can you can break that you
can break the the links in that chain
pretty easily
40% capacity without an attack sorry
okay yeah Anthony
said oh one second here you could read
that one first if you like all right
yeah so here's a great thing to do all
right and I just this is a great so we
can have keep more less stabilize
fluctuate my father uh as I was coming
back from Thailand La this last time six
months ago uh they they tell me as I'm
about ready to get on the plane oh yeah
your dad scheduled for lung surgery for
lung cancer
tomorrow like uh okay uh and they said
well you were coming back anyway so we
thought there's no no point
in R ruining your your trip like all
right uh maybe I could have known this a
little before this but um so he has he
they've cut out they cut out well a
total 35% of one lung and 15% of the
other so it's total 25% of his lungs are
gone so he's got lung capacity he's you
know 75% lung capacity because he's
literally missing 25% of his his lungs
well he used to be a smoker for a long
long time three packs a day for 20 years
but he quit a long time ago however he
kind of sits around the house quite a
bit if
they told what they told them to do is
said look we're going to K we're cutting
off 25% of your lungs however you could
go out and exercise and build up your
lung capacity to better than you had
before the lung
surgery which would be easy because he
wasn't in that great a shape before he's
kind of a fat old guy right so he could
easily double his lung
capacity that's what they're figuring
which would be you know from 75% double
that is 150% of what he had
before he'd be 50% healthier than he was
before that's something I would suggest
that you do is exercise in such a way
that you build your lung capacity and
you're going to exercise your lungs to
build their
capacity some of that's exercising the
rest of your body but most of you want
to build exercise your lungs so we're
going to make the lungs better
more plus we're adding the plus more
lungs better
lungs uh the other thing is we could say
is something a negative something you
say an
attack something triggers these
attacks prevent that that thing from
happening or remove that uh thing uh if
you which is
mucus um for we're talking about asthma
um I have chronic asthma and I I'm able
to con me personally I'm just speaking
from my experience I'm a I'm able to
control it because um first off I get
trick because with asthma you have um
steroid inhalers that you use to keep
your your lungs open uh I there was a
time where I just did because it was
affecting my eyes I stopped taking the
ter steroid inhaler and I realized that
when I was eating certain types of foods
if I was eating fatty foods salty foods
any that was
inflammatory I would get an immediate
asmatic reaction from that type of food
that would create because when you're
you know like when you when there's
inflammation there's mucus so I try my
best to keep the mucus at Bay and I also
um you know I take Coss Coss um help
soothes the the mucous membranes and I
don't get as much um asmatic attack so
there there are ways that you can you
know like like mucus is the the thing
that you have to control in order for
you
to to not have so much symptoms I'm glad
you stated it that way because it's not
the mucus that you're I mean the mucus
is the side effect it's one effect cause
the other effect what causes that effect
to begin with and you say you eat these
certain things that triggers that then
that triggers the other thing right
however if you could just suck the mucus
out when you got it that would work
too you know you or could she fast and
like do like a liquid fast or juice fast
and just well that's an interesting
thing now uh uh fasting here's something
now this is I'm want to point this out
this is I'm gonna tell you something
that I know that I've learned so this is
experiential rather than deductive but
it's that type it's an interesting
effect that occurs when people
fast their body goes into what's called
Aptos and it thinks that you're you know
thinks we're going to be starving so it
cleans out any of
the
uh it fires all the marginal cells it
says you're not up to standard you get
the pink slip it cleans up all these all
these things in your body that are not
quite up to to par and this this could
be really helpful for you it could
actually drast it could improve your
system overall once a once a week fast
now don't fast on water you drink water
but no food and your body will then kill
off the marginal cells and anything else
like that including cancer is believed
to be get cleaned out at this these
cases and you can improve your overall
body it cleans out it does some house
cleaning by this atosis technique I
haven't tried it to be able to test it
so I know myself but I've read about it
and it seems to work and interestingly
enough there seems to be some some uh
some
medicines that will trigger this to
happen and there's there's a there's a
cure for cancer right now a real cheap
cure for cancer and I think it works
based on
osis
interesting okay so allergies allergies
is an interesting thing I have allergies
too I got a lot of allergies and for uh
but I don't have any allergies over in
Asia it's how allergies work allergies
you think of your if you're allergic to
the physical thing but allergies are not
a physical thing allergies are an
information
thing oh yeah I have some your body
misinterprets the uh this stimuli and
acts like you know you're you're dying
it it starts flipping out thinking
you're you know you've got Corona virus
and it's you know tries to you know ramp
everything up and try to attack this
nonthreatening
thing so um It's actually an information
problem one thing you can do is I would
go get an allergy test find out what
you're allergic to
and uh don't be around it for seven
years yeah for sure it's it sounds a
little funny but I actually picked that
number uh for precise reason that's
about how long it takes for your immune
system to rework itself and you won't be
allergic to that anymore I was so
allergic to cats that one time I ended
up having to uh I got cat allergy and I
was starting to have uh anaphylactic
shock my throat was going to close up
and I was going to could have died and
uh just we're on our way to another to
like away from where we were going to
like a hotel so I could wash off and
stay there and I had to jump out of the
car at a gas station in mid night and RI
my clothes off pour water over myself
and do jumping jacks which was kind of
funny to to watch
happening a guy in his underwear at
midnight at a gas station pouring water
over his head doing jumping
jacks
um but but it did
work uh but anyways I completely avoided
cats and I'm now can pet cats and don't
have much much of a problem at all
anymore
yeah I was that allergic to cats and now
I could pet
them
right so not everything but all okay now
am I seeing all the comments no think
Anthony had one here who said you
wouldn't have to build factories in the
United States there would be there are
thousands of of them scattered all
throughout the 48 states steel factories
fabric factories among many others all
of them could be adapted for other
sources they're abandoned so why not
take advantage of them uh yes and we had
one before that factories uh it's
basically same thing
so uh yeah you you could do something of
that nature so there's a lot of
advantages to this now some of those
factories are closed down and you
couldn't just open them back up again
but if instead of putting one big
Factory and try to get economy of scale
if you got economy uh if you didn't have
to transport
things uh if you had if you could adapt
very rapidly if you could change quicker
this is what this agile method that I
developed when I was at Apple instead of
uh allowing us to adapt uh and change
how we go about things M you know make
the next thing quicker uh without having
these big lag times that would that
would there's huge value in that uh that
you kind of miss and one of the things
that I had found as far as missings was
that JP Morgan funny they paid me they
brought me in to teach them how to do
Agile and they wouldn't let me do it
however I did find something else uh
which hopefully they fix and this was
this uh in order to do any work there at
least for the type of work that I was
doing you needed to have this MacBook
Pro MacBook Pro is about
$3,000 um and they needed to set this
MacBook Pro up properly for their
Network and all this stuff so they had
to order the MacBook Pro get it set up
and then have it done and this was
taking 30 days for them to
do well what they would do is once they
decided they were going to bring
somebody in you know somebody to work
hire them they would just say your start
date will be 30 days from now and they
would do the proc set the proc Place
running to get your laptop ready for
your first day and sometimes it' be on
the be ready in the first day and
sometimes be a couple days later well
for whatever reason probably because I
was not a normal type of person that was
being brought in they
totally messed this up they didn't put
the order in so I show up and find out
that there's no laptop and it's going to
take 30 days for me to get a laptop and
I just said okay well I'm gonna be here
this many days at this bill rate this
this is how much this laptop's gonna
cost okay my bill rate times 30 days
which is a lot more than
$3,000 and then I said okay this project
we're working on it's going to have five
people and JP Morgan
Chase their employees and I just I
picked all employees not the employees
that get laptops all employees and said
their profits divided by all their
employees equals $1,600 of profit per
day and uh a waiting 30 days before the
people come in and be a profit makes
that laptop worth like
$40,000 for JP Morgan Chase a laptop is
a St is a stack of Post-it
notes them waiting they they're not
wasting the
$3,000 but they're totally wasting
$40,000 and they didn't even know it it
wasn't on the books right so 40,000 of
implicit costs
yes yeah that's uh and at least the
project I was talking about we had 105
people they were going to hire times
what $40,000
each you know we're talking Millions
just millions of dollars just gone
whereas they could have just had laptops
ready actually one thing I said was kind
of a joke and kind of being very snarky
as I said I wonder if there was this if
there might be this way that JP Morgan
Chase could have maybe something like a
card a special card that could uh that
that that that you could take to a store
and show them this card and and they
could give you a laptop you know there's
go to there's there's a there's a
computer store across the street you can
take this card from JP Morgan Chase and
go get a laptop over
there yeah and it actually you know it
actually you could order a new card a
debit card from JP Morgan and they could
have it to you in five days
wow right they've got the system to do
this and you could go across the street
and by the end of the day have your
laptop if that's what they did instead
of their internal process
yeah makes a lot more
sense geez so we have reached our limit
and uh hold on one second here we've
Leed our time limit so um thank you so
much for uh for giving us the insights
on the cor the Corona virus and uh would
you would you want to come back and talk
more about it or yeah U sure I'll
definely talk more about it or some more
things about it before we sum up I'd
like to sum up some things okay watch to
see if you start getting infections in
your in this country okay particularly
watch to see if uh people locals get
infected from the other people people
coming from China coming here with it
that's an issue but that's not a problem
that's not really a big big problem okay
it's if they start infecting other
people that's where the problem exists
then it spreads yeah um watch the news
the media China is lying to you we know
this we just don't know how much they're
lying uh about things they are
definitely lying uh uh avoid avoid
getting sick that's the biggest thing
you could do you can self-quarantine
yourself oh here's something to show you
about this is something that you need to
know about
these surgical masks this kind of thing
is completely worthless for preventing
you from getting sick you've got to
prevent it from getting in around your
face and around into your nose you also
got to prevent it from getting in your
eyes because your eyes are very
susceptible so if you're G to get a mask
it's got to perfectly cover around there
the n95 types are what you would need
they're miserable to wear for very long
so hope if it gets to that point just
avoid people as much you possibly can
but if you do think you're sick and you
should do this anyways if you think
you're sick put on a surgical mask so
you don't infect other
people and wash your
hands and try this for a chance just so
you get a little feeling of this uh just
pay attention to Everything You Touch
spend an hour or a day uh looking around
at Everything You Touch and carry around
a thing of alcohol and spray your hands
after every time you touch something
that's that you you don't know if it's
clean or not you'll get a better grasp
of what's actually going
on what can we clean our house with if
we can't use bleach you can use bleach
um uh bleach was great it's just that
you uh it's typically people put very
watered down bleach and clean stuff it's
got to be pretty high for Bleach alcohol
work apparently works for this uh
vinegar apparently works for this uh
there's some actual real uh virus sides
that you can get fairly expensive but
you can get those to clean with this um
one of the main things though is if you
just wash it off and you put it you get
it off the surfaces the things that it's
in so far we don't believe that this uh
is Airborne it's in you know when you
cough it's in your spit it's primarily
what goes on so if you wash it off that
goes in there don't touch your face
clean the stuff uh that's us steam is a
great
disinfectant uh if you can get a steamer
uh they're pretty cheap you get one for
50 bucks steam clean everything works
great if you want to go get an ozone but
I would recommend not doing that because
you probably don't know how to use it
properly and you'll end up injuring
yourself
yeah wow uh you know on
uh before we leave there was a a story
not a story but I someone had mentioned
in their Instagram story about their son
coming home and all the kids in the
school were making fun of a Chinese kid
um and saying to stay away from him
because he has the Corona virus now yeah
so and they were using you know racial
um uh what do you call it starts with an
E epets EP epets yes you know and and
whatnot but you know like that's the
other part of this is that you know are
we we're not targeting Chinese people
and just staying away from Chinese
people because
uh because the uh virus comes out of
China I mean it has
to I I I think that especially when
you're living in Canada or when you're
living in the United States you know I
think that we're a little bit more we're
more equipped to to be able to at least
figure out who has the virus and
quarantine them and and whatnot right
and I know Canada is very diligent with
that uh but I'm I'm gonna put a little
bit of a a different view on this okay
okay uh reality doesn't care about your
feelings we're talking about something
that kills
people now it is mean and it's stupid to
pick on some kid some Chinese kid who's
actually Canadian right who's never been
to China as long as his
auntie didn't go to China and come back
uh he's just like everybody else that's
right and kids are mean and kids are
cruel and they do stupid stuff however
at some
point potentially soon you might want to
avoid Chinese people because they've
been exposed to Chinese people from
China and your feelings do not you know
reality does not care about your
feelings so there's a functional
distinction again let's look at what's
actually we're trying to achieve being
mean to people being exclusionary For No
Good Reason stupid for a good reason
okay this is where the disease is coming
from blocking you know staying away from
those people you don't need to be mean
to people for that case that's stupid
but stopping the spread of something is
very important because this could
theoretically kill millions of people
right now it look like it now it's
probably to be small it trapped but this
is the way you should you should look at
this stuff what are you actually trying
to
achieve and so far it's been treated
well in the United States and Canada and
such place everybody who's got who's had
it who's gotten to these places has
recovered looks like we're fine but so
yes I'm agreeing with you and I'm also
pointing out
that if it got bigger or that yeah or if
it looks like it's heading that
direction actually you want to wait
before it gets bigger because once it
gets bigger you're going to be running
from
everybody yeah for sure you know it's
literally the zombie apocalypse at that
point okay well
uh oh man yeah well okay so we we we got
we are um what time is it right now it's
9 9:33 okay so I got um a few more
things we got to do before we leave so
we're in the lightning round uh section
we have those things yes we do okay so
talking or
texting
talking okay favorite day of the
week sleepy day whatever I don't care I
I I don't follow a schedule I don't care
you don't care okay favorite city in the
US besides the one you live
in the ones I don't live in the ones
that you the ones that you that you live
in yeah not the ones I live in that one
I I don't want to live here uh in the
US uh oh man I don't I don't like any of
these in the US
uh if you could pick just one Chicago I
like Chicago I suppose I like Chicago
half of the Year okay uh nicknames your
nickname your parents used to give you I
didn't have a nickname when I was from
my from my parents okay last song you
ever
downloaded uh
probably okay that's actually quite easy
that was uh Highway Star by Deep Purple
because I'm learning the solo to it oh
cool uh would you ra rather be able to
speak every language in the world or be
able to talk to
animals from what I understand animals
are more friendly
uh
although I'm going to find out really
just you know you know I think I would
change my mind it I might change my mind
after I uh talk to the animals for a
while yeah be like who who has the
Corona
virus or like oh this what animals are
thinking H never mind I want to go back
to
people favorite
holiday uh Passover Passover uh how long
does it take for you to get
ready for what for
anything uh between three minutes and
three
hours three minutes and three hours
sometimes I get up and just go for it
sometimes it takes me forever to to just
pick pick yourself up uh scale from one
to 10 how good of a driver are
you I would okay we're talk the Dunning
Dunning Krueger effect here but um I
would have to say I was closer on the
eight or nine
scale I grew up in
Detroit which has which has
snow uh I've been around I've had sports
cars I've done all kinds of things of
this nature I've got a I'm probably and
I know know how the uh how the Asians
drive so they've got to be towards the
one
side because you've experienced it when
you were in Thailand yeah although
interestingly enough after riding a
bicycle in in traffic I much respect the
taxi drivers in Bangkok they don't hit
anybody and it's amazing I would have
thought that they after being one of the
people they should have hit I am stunned
that they don't hit more
people well you know I had this same
experience in Guyana and Jamaica and in
Mexico like it just seems like
uh they go as fast as they want and
whatever side of the road they want
and nothing
happens yeah not lightning for you there
fill in the blank Taylor Swift
is human I guess okay at what age at age
what a at what age do you want to retire
I think I know this answer maybe I don't
but uh 10 years ago 10 years
ago uh invisibility or super
strength I'll take super strength super
strength okay and last question is it
wrong for a vegetarian to eat animal
crackers is it wrong vegetarian
yes it's wrong
for vegetarians are wrong yeah they're
wrong but is it wrong for a vegetarian
or vegan to eat animal
crackers of course they they they get
upset about everything
absolutely awesome
well thank you thank you so much sorry
the you froze there for a few seconds
but anyway well thank you for coming in
did you enjoy yourself yes awesome so we
got one more thing one more tradition
that we have to do before you leave and
um how many how many people are in the
room
there in your maker space Oh just one
just one okay so hopefully they don't
think that you're crazy but I'm gonna do
a call resp
so he's good okay so I'm gonna
say welcome to the and I need you to
scream hustles on as loud as you can
okay okay so welcome to the hustle Zone
hustle Zone okay thank you so much Mark
Mar uh for coming in and I hope you guys
we had we had a few people here we had
uh zika we had Anthony we had uh Carlos
at the beginning uh thank you guys all
for for participating Mark and I are
going to be doing this more often uh
talking about a lot of different
subjects and seeing how they you know
seeing how they mesh with Mark's
predictive Innovation and and how we can
figure things out and how we can you
know solve problems
and U predict
things from happening or what have you
uh so hopefully you guys will be able to
tune in um when we go live and and you
guys can if you send me your email
addresses I can add you to my email list
and so you know that when we're going to
have a show nothing is planned right now
but we're working on it we're just
getting all the technical things out of
the way and once we have that then we'll
have regular planed shows but you know
send me your emails if you want to uh
know when we're going to go live next so
thank you guys all for for for for
joining and I will talk to you guys
later um real quick Roberto contact me
I've got some thoughts for
you
awesome and yeah Roberta I will send you
send me contact information I'll send it
to
Mark oh Mark actually never mind uh how
can we find you oh well Mark profit m a
r k p r ffi tt.com that's my blog uh you
also might want to check out uh and I
didn't do this before but you got
uh roundsquare triangle.com
and predictive Innovation and I'm Mark
profit on on YouTube and uh that's
basically where I'm at um and hopefully
you'll be finding me in and uh 72 uh
suum vit
Bangkok well well hope that this virus
thing kind of kills itself following
your advice because they're gonna all
listen to this podcast and uh make some
changes and everyone will be wearing H
face
masks uh but but anyway talk to you
later mark thank you for for for joining
and thank you to all those who uh watch
this show tonight bye